# YOONJOO LEE

### yoonjoo.lee@kaist.ac.kr | yoonjoolee.com

# RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interest lies in the intersection of human-computer interaction (HCI) and natural language processing (NLP). I aim to support people to learn from and make sense of dense information (e.g., content in lecture videos and scientific articles) by structuring the information in the context to create adaptive scaffoldings (e.g., QAs, dialogues, explanations) using AI models.

### **EDUCATION**

KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science. Advisor: Juho Kim

Sep. 2020 – Present

Ewha Womans University Seoul, Republic of Korea

M.S. in Statistics (Applicational Statistics). Advisor: Dongwan Shin B.S. Major in Mathematics Education, Minor in Statistics

Graduated with Honors (Magna Cum Laude)

Mar. 2018 – Feb. 2020 Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

Mar. 2014 – Feb. 2018

University of California, Davis

Exchange student in Mathematics

**Davis, CA, USA** Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016

# **PUBLICATIONS**

### **Conference and Journal Papers**

[C7] QASA: Advanced Question Answering on Scientific Articles

**Yoonjoo Lee**\*, Kyungjae Lee\*, Sunghyun Park, Dasol Hwang, Jaehyeon Kim, Hong-in Lee, Moontae Lee *ICML 2023: Proceedings of the 40th International Conference on Machine Learning* 

[C6] Cells, Generators, and Lenses: Design Framework for Object-Oriented Interaction with Large Language Models

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

UIST 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (to appear).

[C5] DAPIE: Interactive Step-by-Step Explanatory Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Sundong Kim, Yohan Yun, Juho Kim

CHI 2023: Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C4] Promptiverse: Scalable Generation of Scaffolding Prompts Through Human-AI Hybrid Knowledge Graph Annotation

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Tae Soo Kim, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

CHI 2022: Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

[C3] Personalizing Ambience and Illusionary Presence: How People Use "Study with Me" Videos to Create Effective Studying Environments

Yoonjoo Lee, John Joon Young Chung, Jean Y. Song, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

CHI 2021: Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems.

[C2] A Machine Learning Approach that meets Axiomatic Properties in Probabilistic Analysis of LTE Spectral Efficiency

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

ICTC, Oct. 2019

Last Updated: November 3, 2023

### [C1] Probabilistic Analysis of Spectral Efficiency for LTE based on PDCCH Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Yeonkyu Park, Seungken Park

IEEE Communications Letters, vol. 23, no. 9, Sep. 2019

# **Preprints**

# [A1] EvalLM: Interactive Evaluation of Large Language Model Prompts on User-Defined Criteria

Tae Soo Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Juho Kim

Under Review, 2023

# **Posters and Workshop Papers**

# [P5] LMCanvas: Object-Oriented Interaction to Personalize Large Language Model-Powered Writing Environments

Tae Soo Kim, Arghya Sarkar, Yoonjoo Lee, Minsuk Chang, and Juho Kim

CHI 2023 Workshop on Generative AI and HCI

### [P4] Interactive Children's Story Rewriting Through Parent-Children Interaction

Yoonjoo Lee, Tae Soo Kim, Minsuk Chang, Juho Kim

ACL 2022 Workshop on Intelligent and Interactive Writing Assistant

### [P3] XDesign: Integrating Interface Design into Explainable AI Education

Hyungyu Shin, Nabila Sindi, Yoonjoo Lee, Jaeryoung Ka, Jean Y. Song, Juho Kim

SIGCSE TS 2022 Posters

### [P2] A Study on the Distribution Analysis of LTE Resource Block Usage from TSME Measurement Data

Yoonjoo Lee, Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# [P1] A Study on the Estimation of Probability Distribution of the Spectral Efficiency of LTE based on TSME Measurement Data

Yunbae Kim, Yoonjoo Lee, Seungken Park

KICS, Jun. 2018

# **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

Allen Institute for AI (AI2)

Seattle, US

Research Scientist Intern, Semantic Scholar Team May - Oct. 2023

Mentor: Pao Siangliulue, Joseph Chee Chang, Jonathan Bragg, Kyle Lo

LG AI Research Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Scientist Intern, Advanced Machine Learning Lab
Mentor: Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee

[C6]

KIXLAB, KAIST Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Graduate Research Intern

Mar. 2020 – Aug. 2020

Mentor: Juho Kim, Jean Y. Song

### **Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)**

Graduate Research Assistant, Data Sciences Group

Mentor: Yunbae Kim, Seungken Park [P1, P2, C1, C2]

Last Updated: November 3, 2023

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Mar. 2018 – Dec. 2019

# **TEACHING**

**Introduction to Social Computing** 

Fall 2020, Fall 2021

KAIST CS473, Instructor: Juho Kim

Time Series Analysis Spring 2019

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Dongwan Shin

Regression Analysis Fall 2018

Ewha Womans University, Instructor: Donghwan Lee

# **ACADEMIC SERVICES**

## **Program Committee**

• CHI LBW 2023

### Reviewer

- EMNLP 2023
- CHI 2024, 2023, 2022
- UIST 2022, 2023
- ACL 2023
- CSCW 2023
- C&C 2022
- IEEE Transactions on Learning Technologies

#### **Student Volunteer**

CHI 2022

### **INVITED TALKS**

<b>Technical Talk at NAVER AI LAB</b> Title: Creating Interactive Dialogues to Answer Children's Why and How Questions	Nov. 2023
Invited Talk at UCSD Design Lab	Oct. 2023

Invited Talk at UCSD Design Lab

Title: Adapting Scaffolding to Support Knowledge Consumption through Interactive AI-Driven Systems

Invited Talk at University of Washington Oct. 2023

Title: Adapting Scaffolding to Support Knowledge Consumption through Interactive AI-Driven Systems

### HONORS, AWARDS, AND SCHOLARSHIPS

# Research Assistant Scholarship College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Admission Scholarship 2018

College of Natural Sciences, Ewha Womans University

Honors Scholarship 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Dean's List 2014, 2015, 2016, 2017

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Ewha Womans University Alumnae Association Scholarship

College of Education, Ewha Womans University

Last Updated: November 3, 2023

2017

# **SERVICE AND LEADERSHIP**

KAIST-Google ExploreCSR
Student Organizer

2022

Programming Mentoring 2016 – 2017

Leader of Student Organizer

Last Updated: November 3, 2023